おお～　いらっしゃい。
いらっしゃい　いらっしゃい。
Take a look, take a gander!
（ブーデル）いや～　旦那様→
Why Master, you look as dashing as ever today!
今日も　いい男っぷりで。
それも　そのはず→
財宝を　あんなことに使うとは
気前よすぎですよ。→
You're such a generous man, using your treasures to pay me back.
ええ。　さあさあ　こちらへ。→
Come, please partake!
I've arranged for you to have the most
beautiful women and the highest quality wine.
私めも
極上の酒と女を　用意しましたぞ。
（アリババ）あのさぁ
俺なんかのご機嫌　取って→
Uh...
Doesn't having to talk like that to me bother you?
恥ずかしくねぇの？
全然。
Not at all!
はぁ…。
It's already been three days.
（心の声）
≪あれから　もう３日だぞ≫
≪どこ行ったんだよ　アラジン≫
Where did Aladdin go?
Master Alibaba.
≪アリババ様→
子供のお客様が　いらっしゃってます。
あっ！
There's a child here to see you.
I missed you, Aladdin!
おかえり　アラジン！
あっ。
（モルジアナ）どうして　財宝を使って→
Why did you use your treasure to free us slaves?
私たち奴隷を　解放したんですか？
あいつなら　こうしたかなって。
'Cause I figured that's what Aladdin would've done.
みんな　あなたに感謝しています。
Everyone is really grateful to you.
おそらく　私も
感謝をしているんだと思います→
I think I may be grateful too.
あなたと　ご友人のあの少年に。
To both you and that boy.
What are you going to do now?
これから　どうするんだ？
いつか　故郷へ帰ります。
Someday, I will return to my homeland.
That is what my benefactor wanted.
恩人の言葉ですから。
恩人の言葉か。　そうだよな→
His last wish, huh?
You've already made up your mind.
I need to make up my mind too.
俺も　いいかげんに決めないと。
♪♪～
≪あの言葉　本当にうれしかった≫
I was so happy when he said that to me.
You're no coward.
（アラジン・回想）
((君は　卑怯者なんかじゃないよ))
((勇気ある人だよ　絶対に))
You're a hero!
≪アラジン
俺は　やるべきことをやりながら→
Aladdin, I'll no longer skirt along the path I must
walk. But I'll be searching for you the whole way!
お前を捜す。　そして→
Let's find each other and go on another adventure together!
また　一緒に冒険をしよう≫
♪♪～
akogare wo ima tsukanda
My desires are within reach.
daikansei no namari ni
If the loud, welcoming cheers
kokochiyoku utaretanara
shoot home straight into your heart,
saa tobikomou
then come and jump in!
ashita kara umare kawaru toka
People say they'll change the next day.
♪♪～
dareka ga mikiri tsuketa toka
But they give up so easily.
kono machi no style toka
That's just how it is here.
sonna mono ni nagasare tsuzukete
They get swept away by those excuses day by day.
kado no toreta genseki ni ha
They're nothing more than a chip, swept off the edge
kitto daremo you ha nai
and no longer needed by anyone.
♪♪～
fushigi to tobira no mukou ni ha
Guess what? Out there,
v.i.p nanoru yatsu ha naku
no one's swaggering around like a VIP.
daremo ga kunou no hate sa ore mo
Everyone suffers their own heartaches, myself included.
akogare wo ima tsukanda
But my desires are within reach.
♪♪～
mi wo yudanereba ii  kaji ha kono te ni
Throw yourself in with abandon. I've got the wheel.
mitsu kazoete the show time
On the count of three, it's show time!
daikansei no namari ni
If the loud, welcoming cheers
kokochiyoku utaretanara
shoot home straight into your heart,
saa tobikomou
then come and jump in!
♪♪～
((ねえ))
Hey...
What exactly am I?
((僕って　なんだい？))
Tell me!
((答えてよ))
Why won't you say anything?
((なぜ　何も言わないんだ!?))
4th Night
The People
of the Plains
≪（ババ）お目覚めかい？
ルフの子や。→
Have you awakened, child of the rukh?
ふふふふっ。→
You look very refreshed.
元気になったようじゃのう。→
ルフが喜んでおる。
The rukh are pleased.
ルフ？
（ババ）そこいらを飛んでおるよ。
The rukh?
They are flying there.
あっ　おばあちゃんにも見えるの？
Granny, you can see them?
That I can.
ああ。→
They are visible to you as well?
お主にも見えるのか？→
この無数の命の流動が。
Can you see the embodiments of the never-ending flow of life?
ピィ　ピィ　ピィ　ピィ…（ルフの声）
うわ～！
What exactly is the rukh?
ねえ　ルフって　何なんだい？
（ババ）ルフとはな→
The rukh is the home of the soul.
すなわち　魂の故郷。→
All those that are living will eventually pass. When that time comes, they will all return to a single place.
生きとし生けるものは　死ねば皆→
一つの場所へと帰ってゆく。→
The body returns to the soil, but the soul returns to the rukh.
肉体は　土に帰り　魂は　ルフへと→
帰ってゆくのじゃよ。
彼らには助けてもらうばかりだな。
ん？
I'm always being saved by them.
What was that?
When I share the power inside of my stomach,
僕の　おなかの力を
分けてあげるとね→
光の粒が集まってきて→
those particles of light gather,
and lend me their power.
僕に　力を貸してくれるんだ。
My child! What you say is...
なんと！　それは…。
≪パサッ
≪（トーヤ）おばあちゃん。
（ババ）どうした？　トーヤ。
Granny?
What is it, Touya?
The scouting party has returned.
（トーヤ）偵察隊が　帰って来ました。
（ババ）うむ　分かった。
So they have.
うわ～！
♪♪～
Can you see them?
（ババ）見えるか？
うん。
Yes.
ヒヒーン（馬の鳴き声）
（トーヤ）おかえり　ドルジ。
Welcome back, Dolge.
（ドルジ）おう！
ケガしなかった？
Thanks!
Did you get hurt?
（ドルジ）あ…　ああ…。
（トーヤ）ドルジが→
Dolge is the one who found you
unconscious and brought you back.
倒れてた君を　連れてきたんだよ。
I'm fine now.
≫（ドルジ）もう大丈夫か？
（ババ）東は　どうじゃった？
Thank you, mister.
What did you find in the east?
また一つ　村が　侵略されました。
Another village has been invaded.
≪（ドルジ）大丈夫だ　ババ様。→
Don't worry, Elder Baba.
The Kouga Clan has managed to avoid the greedy hands of other nations for hundreds of years.
俺たち黄牙の一族は→
何百年も　他国の手を
はねのけてきたじゃねぇか。→
We'll slap them away this time too!
今度も　蹴散らしてやろうぜ。
≪ああ。
≪そうだ。
（ドルジ）一族の誇りのために！
（一同）おお～！
For the pride of our clan!
プーーッ（笛の音）
（一同）うわ～～!!
ヒヒーン！
（ドルジ）何なんだ？　お前は。
What are you?
Are you a spy from Kou?
（バートル）煌帝国のスパイか!?
（トーヤ）こんな子が
スパイなわけないじゃない。
There's no way this child is a spy.
（ドルジ）それも　そうだが…。
I guess that's true.
（ボヤン）
名前は？　どこから来たんだ？
What's your name?
Where did you come from?
I'm Aladdin.
僕は　アラジンさ。
I was in a town called Qishan. Do you know of it?
チーシャンという町に
いたんだけど　知らないかい？
聞いたことがある。
西のかなたにあって→
I've heard of it.
It's supposedly beyond the western lands
and takes about two years to reach by foot.
歩くと
２年はかかると言ってたな。
What? It's that far away?
ええ～！　そんなに遠いのかい？
はぁ…。
大丈夫じゃよ。
No need to fret. If you ride with the caravans that will arrive in two weeks, you will be fine.
２週間後に来るキャラバンに
乗せてもらえばよい。
えっ？
早く帰れるよ。
What?
It will not be such a long trip by caravan.
Thank goodness!
よかった～！
そんなに　早く帰りたいの？
Do you want to go back that badly?
うん。
ふふっ。
Yes.
I made a promise with a friend, you see.
友達との約束があるからね。
≪はははっ。
≫ああ～　はははっ！
にぎやかだね。
Everyone's so happy and excited!
We are one big family here.
大家族じゃからのう。
み～んな　家族なの？
（ババ）そうさ。→
Everyone here is family?
That they are, my child.
我らは
何百年もの間　共に生きてきた→
Our people have lived together for
hundreds of years. We are of the same blood.
同じ血の流れる家族じゃ。
ふ～ん。
（ウーゴ）
((あなたに　家族はいません。→
You do not have family.
あなたは
ほかの人間とは　まったく違う→
You are completely different from other people.
特異な存在なのです))
You are a singularity.
All one family...
家族か…。　いいね。
That's nice.
（ババ）何を言っとる。
ん？
You do not see.
Huh?
The people of the plains are one
with all those who share our lives.
（ババ）草原の民は
共に暮らせば一心同体。→
You are also family.
お主も　もう　我らが家族。
ババの子じゃ。
You are also one of my beloved children.
わあ～！
おばあちゃん　大好き！
（ババ）はははっ。
I love you, Granny!
グキッ！
（ババ）ああっ！　あっ…。
"Kou"
わあ～　おいしいね！
ん？→
This is so delicious!
ああ～！　直接　飲んじゃダメ！
No, stop! You can't drink that directly from the horse!
She said stop.
（ドルジ）ダメだっつってんだろ。
あっ。
ひどいよ　おにいさん。
（ドルジ）変なガキだぜ。→
Mister, you're mean!
What a weird kid.
It's really nice out today, huh?
今日は　天気がいいな。
うん。　その刀は？
Yeah... What's that sword for?
いざってときのためにさ。
Just in case.
戦わなくちゃならない日なんて
来なければいいよね。→
It'd be nice if that just in case never came.
I hope we are never forced to fight.
ずっと　こうやって→
I wish we could just live here in peace forever.
みんなで暮らしていけたら
幸せだよね。
心配するなよ　トーヤ。
俺が　絶対　守ってやるから。
Don't worry, Touya.
I'll always protect you.
≪ヒヒーン！
ん？
うわぁ～～！
止めねぇと！
うわぁ～！
Shoot, I've got to stop him!
アラジン！
Aladdin!
うわぁ～～！　わぁ…。
ああ～…　おっ。
（白瑛）大丈夫ですか？　少年。
あっ。
Are you all right, young man?
（白瑛）ふふっ。
（白瑛）
私は　煌帝国　初代皇帝が第三子→
I am the third daughter of the first Kou emperor, Hakuei Ren.
練白瑛。
外交のお話をしに参りました。
I have come to engage in diplomatic talks with you.
（ババ）ようこそ　姫君。→
Welcome, esteemed daughter.
I am the granddaughter of the 155th great king of the Kouga Clan.
私は　黄牙一族→
第１５５代大王が孫娘→
チャガン・シャマンと申します。
I am called Shaman Chagan.
（白瑛）
存じております。　黄牙一族は→
I am aware.
The Kouga Clan was once the most
prosperous equestrian tribe in the world.
かつて最も栄えた騎馬民族。→
初代大王は　魔人のごとき力で→
The first great king of the Kouga Clan
supposedly had powers rivaling a demon's,
歴史上最大の国　大黄牙帝国を→
and built the largest nation known to man: the Great Kouga Empire.
築いたと聞いております。→
ですが　近年では　弱体化し
奴隷狩りの被害にまで→
In recent years, the Kouga Clan has weakened and has even been targeted by slave hunters.
遭っているとか。
（一同）くっ！
But today, that suffering is at an end.
しかし　その苦労も　今日までです。
我々の傘下に　お入りなさい。
Please come under our empire!
Go under them?
≪傘下だと？
What kind of request is that?
（ドルジ）なんだ　それ…。
（ボヤン）ありえねぇ。
No way!
（白瑛）我々は　西のレーム→
We aspire to unify the land, from Laem in the west to Partevia in the southwest.
西南のパルテビアらの統一→
Our goal is to unify the whole world.
つまりは
世界統一を志しています。→
黄牙のご先祖様と　同じ夢です。→
The same as your Kouga ancestors once dreamed of doing.
Please lend us your strength.
どうか　お力添えを。
Our ancestors?
≫ご先祖様？
≪同じ夢？
Our dreams?
どうしたの？　ウーゴくん。
What's the matter, Ugo?
In other words, you want to take over our village.
（ドルジ）つまり　俺たちの村を→
侵略するってことだろ？
（バートル）そうだよな？
Isn't that what you mean?
≪ああ！
≫よそへ入ってたまるか！
As if we would let outsiders like you in here!
（ババ）ええい！　静まれ！
Quiet!
Esteemed daughter, do not be so impatient.
姫君よ　そう焦るでない。
（呂斎）ふん。
≪（トーヤ）あの…→
Excuse me.
I've prepared some horse milk spirits. Would you like to continue this conversation inside?
馬乳酒を　お入れしましたので→
中で
ゆっくり　お話ししませんか？
（白瑛）まあ　ありがとう。
Thank you.
ああっ！
あっ！
Ryosai!
（白瑛）呂斎　何をするのです！
What do you think you're doing?
（呂斎）尊い姫様に　馬の乳など
飲ませらんないんですよ。
I cannot allow the noble princess to drink something like horse milk.
Ryosai!
（青舜）呂斎！
（呂斎）おい　貴様ら！→
Listen up, you rabble!
この村は
今から　煌帝国の統制下に入る。
This village is now under the control of the Kou Empire.
（一同）えっ!?
（呂斎）速やかに　服従せよ。→
You will submit quietly!
こんな臭くて汚い生活から
救い出してやるんだ。→
We're saving you from this crude, dirty lifestyle, after all.
悪い話じゃないだろ？
It's a good deal, no?
（ドルジ）うおぉ～～!!
ガキン！
（ドルジ）くっ！
（青舜）
この者を斬るは　宣戦布告と同じ。
Killing this man is the same as a declaration of war.
それを望まれるか？
Is that what you desire?
How dare you hurt my family!
よくも　家族を！
≪（ババ）やめんか　ドルジ！
Stop, Dolge.
ちっ！
お前も　控えなさい。
You will stand down as well, Ryosai.
この場は　引きます。
We are withdrawing.
Why did you stop me?
（呂斎）
なぜ　お止めになったのです？→
We had the perfect opportunity to get rid of those Kouga people.
Kou
A
異民族どもを葬る　絶好の機会→
How could you let that slip away?
それを　みすみす…。
They are future citizens of the Kou Empire.
彼らは　未来の煌国民です。
最善の策を考えましょう。
We must come up with the best strategy we can.
それが　よろしいかと。
くっ！
I believe that is for the best.
今後のことは
明朝までに決めます。
I will come up with something by tomorrow morning.
はぁ…。
将軍として
皆を　しっかり　まとめなければ…。
I must somehow get everyone to follow me as a general.
≫こんばんは！
あっ。
Good evening!
こんばんは　おねえさん。
Hello there, miss.
やあ。　僕は　アラジン。
Hi!
I'm Aladdin.
ちょっと　お話ししたくて
やってきたのさ。
I wanted to talk with you.
≪あの布は…≫
That cloth...
I would like to speak to you as well.
私も　君と話がしてみたい。
（白瑛）
それは　迷宮アイテムですね？
That is a Dungeon Item, isn't it?
えっ？
人知を超えた力を宿す→
A device with power beyond human understanding.
不思議な道具。
それを手にするのは→
They can only be acquired by those who have cleared a dungeon.
迷宮から生還した者のみ。
これは→
This is something that I've always had.
もともと持っていたものだよ。
えっ？
What?
おねえさんは
あの村を侵略する人なのかい？
Are you going to take over that village, miss?
If so, I would like you to stop.
なら　やめてほしいんだ。
おばあちゃんが　泣いてしまうよ。
Granny will be so sad.
僕に　家族を教えてくれた
大好きな人たちなんだ。
Granny and the others taught me the meaning of family. They're very important to me.
殺さないで。
Don't kill them.
♪♪～
殺しなどしません…　決して。→
I will not kill anyone.
Not a single soul.
私は　正しい力と心で
世界を一つにまとめ→
I want to create a unified world where no one will have to die needlessly.
誰も死なぬ世の中を
作りたいのです。→
I have but good intentions and only want to use my power for good.
どうか信じてください。
Please believe me.
ピィ　ピィ　ピィ…
♪♪～
ふふっ。
おねえさんの周りのルフは→
The rukh around you show not even the smallest bit of doubt, miss.
痛いほど迷いがないね。
I understand. I will try to talk to Granny and the others.
分かったよ。
おばあちゃんたちに話してみるね。
♪♪～
Ugo, what happened when we first met that lady?
ウーゴくん
あのおねえさんに出会ったとき→
どうしたんだい？
あとさ　前の迷宮で→
And what were you talking about with Amon in the dungeon?
アモンくんと　何を話したんだい？
I see. It's okay!
そっか。　大丈夫だよ→
I know there are things you can't tell me.
答えられないことがあるのは
分かっている。
I will search the world to my heart's content to figure out who I am.
僕は　思うままに
僕のことを探ってみるよ。
I have a feeling that I can learn something here in this village.
この村で　何かが分かる→
そんな予感がしているんだ。
ピィ　ピィ　ピィ　ピィ…
なんだろう？
What's going on?
ヤツらめ…　絶対に許さねぇ！→
They're so dead!
いくぞ！
（一同）おお～！
Let's go!
敵は　決して殺すな。
You are absolutely not to kill anyone.
１人でも殺せば　戦争になる。→
If you kill even one of them, there will be war.
Do you understand?
よいな!?
頼むぞ！
I am counting on you!
無事に　連れ帰ってくれ…。
Please bring them back safely...
≫ドーン！
はっ！
どうしたの？　おばあちゃん。
What happened, Granny?
お主は　一体…。
What on earth...
♪♪～
Hold on, Touya!
待ってろ　トーヤ。
♪♪～
へっ！　こいつらは　丈夫な一族だ。
What a great, strong clan.
You're going to make me a rich man for all eternity.
末永く　金儲けに使うぞ。
どうするんで？
（トーヤ）あっ！　うっ…。
What are you going to do?
（隊長）
延々と　子供をつくらせるんだよ。
She's going to be my breeding horse.
あっ…　うぅ…。
（隊長）繁殖させれば→
As long as she can have kids, I'll have slaves and therefore riches.
ずっと儲けられる。
んん…。
What was that? You don't like my plan?
なんだ？
文句でもあるのか？　ないよな？
Of course you do.
（トーヤ）うっ！　あっ！
（隊長）へへへへっ。
Captain!
≫（隊員）隊長　追っ手です！
（隊長）あん!?
We have pursuers!
What?
Touya!
（ドルジ）トーヤ！
ええい！　射殺せ！
Shoot them!
Fire!
撃て！
♪♪～
Shoot! Fire!
（隊長）ええい！　撃て　撃て！
♪♪～
（隊長）くっ…　近づけるな！
Stay away!
♪♪～
ドカッ！
（隊長）ぐわっ！
Don't you dare look down on the Kouga clan.
（ドルジ）
黄牙の一族を　なめんじゃねぇ。
来るな！
ガキン！
Stay away!
If you kill even one of them, there will be war.
（ババ）
((１人でも殺せば　戦争になるぞ))
くっ…。
あっ…。
くっ！
ひぃ！
貴様～～！
You bastard!
ドン　ドン　ドン　ドン…（足音）
見失ってしまったよ。
I've lost them.
ここで待つのじゃ。
でも…。
We will wait for them here.
But...
They are fine warriors of the Kouga Clan.
ヤツらとて　立派な黄牙の戦士じゃ。
信じてやっとくれ。
Believe in them.
うん。
Okay.
Child who can call on the power of the rukh, who can summon a giant,
（ババ）
しかし　巨人を使い　ルフを使い→
アラジンは　まるで
おとぎ話のマギのようじゃなぁ。
you are like the Magi of the old tales.
マギを知ってるの？
（ババ）ああ。　知っとるよ。
Do you know of the Magi?
That I do.
ねえ　教えて。　マギって　なんだい？
What is a Magi? Won't you tell me?
僕は　そのマギかもしれない。
I might be a Magi.
僕は　自分が何者なのか
探しているんだ。
I am trying to figure out what I am.
♪♪～
（ババ）まだ　この世に
国がなかった頃の話じゃ。
This is a tale from a time when there were no countries.
（ババ）厄災に苦しむ人々の前に→
During a time of calamity and disaster, a young man appeared before the people and said:
一人の青年が現れ　言いました。→
「人間よ…　国を作り→
Humans, create a country.
王のもと　団結して生きなさい。→
Come together and live under a king.
The power to be king may be gained by overcoming the trials of this tower.
王たる力は
この塔で　試練を乗り越え→
得られるだろう」。
Untold numbers went into the tower, never to return.
たくさんの人が　塔へと消え→
やがて　戻った一人が
王として　国を築き→
Finally, one did, and became king.
平穏が訪れました。
A country was made and peace reigned.
The people greatly respected the mysterious young man who gave them that prophecy.
人々は　その不思議な青年を→
尊敬を込めて
こう呼んだそうです→
They called him the Magi.
「マギ」と。
あっ。
The country created in that story is the one we call the Great Kouga Empire.
（ババ）そのとき　作られた国こそ→
我らが大黄牙帝国と
いわれておるんじゃ。
♪♪～
I see! So that's a Magi...
そっか。　それが　マギか。
But Aladdin...
時に　アラジン。
ん？
Hm?
You asked what you are.
お主は　何者かと言ったが→
今は
ババの子である　アラジンじゃよ。
Right now, you are Aladdin, my child.
えっ？
（ババ）友達は　おらんのか？
Do you have any you call friends?
いるよ。
ウーゴくんと　アリババくん。
I do.
Ugo and Alibaba.
Then you are Aladdin, friend of Ugo and Alibaba.
ならば　お主は
ウーゴとアリババの友達である→
アラジンじゃ。
あっ。
Oh.
ほっほっほっほっ。
おかしいのう。
ババは　お主が何者か→
Isn't that just the strangest? This old
granny knows very well who you are.
こんなに知っておったよ。
うん！　ありがとう　おばあちゃん。
Thanks, Granny.
You know what?
あのね。
なんだい？
What is it, child?
I met with the Kou princess yesterday
僕は　昨日
煌帝国のお姫様に会って→
and she promised me she would not kill anyone.
殺し合わない約束をしたんだ。
So don't worry. There will not be a war.
だから
戦争は起こらないよ。　大丈夫。
Everything will be okay!
お…　お主は…。
ほら！
Y-You...
Look!
They've returned.
みんなが　帰って来た。
♪♪～
おお！
Elder Baba!
（ドルジ）ババ様～！　全員　無事だ。→
Everyone's fine!
We were able to rescue everyone without killing a single person!
１人も殺さず　助け出しました！
おお…。
I remembered your words.
（ドルジ）
ババ様の言葉を思い出したんだ。→
If I killed one of them, we would have a war on our hands.
敵を殺せば　戦争になる。→
If that happened, we'd no longer be able to spend our days together.
そうしたら
みんなで暮らせはしない。→
だから…。
That's why...
((あっ…))
((くっ！))
((ひぃ…))
（ドルジ）((はぁ　はぁ…))
（ドルジ）だから…。　ふふっ。
（トーヤ）ふふっ。
That's why.
Wonderful, Dolge.
（ババ）立派じゃぞ　ドルジ。
（ドルジ）痛っ！→
Ow!
痛ぇよ　ババ様。
（一同）ははははっ！
That hurt, Elder Baba!
♪♪～
We will surrender ourselves to the Kou Empire.
我々は　帝国に下ろう。
あっ。
（ババ）
我々が守るべきものは　なんだ？→
What is it that we absolutely must protect?
Is it our clan?
国か？　誇りか？　いや　違う…→
Our pride?
No.
It is our lives.
それは　我々の命じゃ。
何があっても
戦争をしてはいかん！→
No matter what happens, we must not choose war.
一族全員で　今を生き抜くための→
Wage war in your hearts instead. Wage a war to live on as a family.
心の戦をせよ。
♪♪～
（一同）はい！
Yes!
♪♪～
It's so warm.
あったかいね。
Here.
（ドルジ）これ。
（トーヤ）ありがとう。
Thank you.
♪♪～
Time to become a man, Dolge.
（ババ）男になれよ　ドルジ。
（ドルジ）顔が　やらしいぞ　ババ様！
（ババ）ははははっ。
You're making a perverted face, Elder Baba!
（一同）ははははっ！
♪♪～
Where are you going?
（ドルジ）どこ行くんだよ？
（ババ）ああ～　便所じゃ　便所。
Just to relieve myself!
♪♪～
（ババ）≪わしは
何を迷っておったんじゃろう。→
What caused me to be so disoriented?
わしの役目は
ただ　家族を生かすこと≫
My role is simply to keep our family alive.
≪そうじゃ…
わしの愛しい子供らの→
I must also live on,
until I can see the faces of my beloved children's
ひ孫　やしゃごの顔を見るまでは→
great-grandchildren and great-great-grandchildren.
皆と共に
わしも　生き抜いてゆかねばのう≫
ドスッ！（矢が刺さる音）
≫はははっ。
おばあちゃん　まだかな？
I hope Granny gets back soon!
♪♪～
nozoite miyou
Take a look
yubi bouenkyou
through your finger telescope.
me ni mieru sekai ha subete kako no monogatari sa
The world you see before your eyes is a story already told.
♪♪～
kagayaku mirai wo miushinau na yo
Don't lose sight of the bright future ahead.
♪♪～
kimi ni ha motto ippai yume to kibou ga arun da
You're destined to realize great hopes and dreams.
bootto shitetara minogashichau zo
But if you blink for too long, they'll leave you behind.
♪♪～
dekinai riyuu sagasu yori
Instead of searching for an excuse,
yatte mireba ii
why not just give it a try?
nozoite miyou
Take a look
yubi bouenkyou
through your finger telescope.
♪♪～
yubi to yubi wo marume ryoume ni ate
Make circles with your fingers and put them around your eyes.
imeeji shite sagashiteru mono
Picture your hopes and dreams!
♪♪～
atama no naka no adobenchaaa
Picture your personal adventure story!
doko he mukau?
Where are you headed?
yubi bouenkyou
What can you see
♪♪～
yubi no sono sukima ni nani ga mieru?
in the space between your fingers?
tooi you demo hontou ha chikai
It might seem far, but it's really not.
yogen no you na takaramono
It's a promise as valuable as any treasure!
It is war, Princess.
I refuse to allow it to come to that.
I made a promise with him!
Next time: Dungeon Capturer.
5th Night
Dungeon Capturer
Hey, no fair! I wanted to meet the princess too!
（呂斎）さあ　戦争ですよ　姫様。
（白瑛）絶対にさせません。
あの少年に　約束したのだから。
くそ～
俺も　姫さんに会いたかった。
昨日、高知市の下水道工事現場で
男性作業員２人が生き埋めになっ
た事故で
現場では、発生から１日以上たっ
た今も、
救出活動が続いている。